logicaldoc.com 2019-06-02

# Privacy Policy

### **Introduction**

We at LogicalDOC Srl take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information that can personally reference you, such as your name, address, email addresses, IP address, etc. The following policy provides you with information about the collection of personal data 1. in relation to the administration of the contractual relationship between you and LogicalDOC Srl, and 2. your responsible use of the functionalities of our LogicalDOC product, consisting of the Software as well as all the related Services (hereinafter collectively referred to as “ **LogicalDOC** ”).

  1. [Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with LogicalDOC.](https://www.logicaldoc.com/t#data-protection-information-concerning-your-contractual-relationship-with-logicaldoc)
    1. [Controller](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#controller)
    2. [Data Protection Officer](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#data-protection-officer)
    3. [Catagories of Data](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#catagories-of-data)
    4. [Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#purpose-and-legal-basis-for-processing)
    5. [Recipients](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#recipients)
    6. [Retention Periods for Personal Data](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#retention-periods-for-personal-data)
    7. [Statutory/contractual requirement](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#statutory-contractual-requirement)
    8. [Automatic Decision-making and Profiling](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#automatic-decision-making-and-profiling)
    9. [Your Rights](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#your-rights)
  2. [Information concerning your responsible use of the Product](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#information-concerning-your-responsible-use-of-the-product)
    1. [Personal Data processed through your use of LogicalDOC](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#personal-data-processed-through-your-use-of-logicaldoc)
    2. [Data Usage](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#data-usage)
    3. [Data Subjects Rights](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#data-subjects-rights)

### **1. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with LogicalDOC**

#### **A. Controller**

LogicalDOC Srl, via Aldo Moro 3 - 41012 Carpi (Italy), is your contractual partner and controller of your personal data in accordance with Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”). For information on data processing in relation to your responsible use of the functionalities of the Software as well as all the related services please refer to the [information concerning the use of LogicalDOC](https://www.logicaldoc.com/privacy-policy#information-concerning-your-responsible-use-of-the-product).

#### **B. Data Protection Officer**

LogicalDOC Srl appointed Marco Meschieri as data protection officer, who can be reached at m.meschieri [at] logicaldoc.com

#### **C. Categories of Data**

##### **I. Download LogicalDOC:**

When you download LogicalDOC to your computer, LogicalDOC Srl collects your **IP address** and **name**.

##### **II. Signing up for LogicalDOC:**

When you sign up for LogicalDOC, LogicalDOC Srl collects your **name, email address** , physical address, phone, company name.

##### **III. License Auditing:**

We will collect information about the **frequency of your use** of the Software and statistics of usage of the different features.

##### **IV. Feedback:**

When you provide a feedback concerning your LogicalDOC experience, LogicalDOC Srl collects your **IP address** and your **email address** , if you chose to provide us with therewith. If you attach LogicalDOC **log files** or **screen shots** , LogicalDOC Srl will also collect these.

##### **V. Paid license and servivces:**

When you purchase a LogicalDOC license or service, LogicalDOC Srl additionally collects **information to support payment processing** , which includes a payment token provided by our Payment Service Provider to identify the transaction.

##### **VI. Newsletter:**

If you sign up for our newsletter, LogicalDOC Srl collects your **email address, name, country and company name**. LogicalDOC Srl uses the so-called double opt-in method by which you receive a confirmation email after you provided us with your email address.

##### **VII. Support:**

When you contact our support we will collect your **name, time** and **date** of your request and your **email address** if you contacted us via email, otherwise your **telephone number** if you contacted us via telephone.

#### **D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing**

##### **I. Download LogicalDOC:**

When you download LogicalDOC, LogicalDOC Srl processes your personal data to provide you with the option to use LogicalDOC. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined above under C. I. is a user agreement concerning the use of LogicalDOC, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

##### **II. Signing up for LogicalDOC:**

When you sign up to LogicalDOC, LogicalDOC Srl uses your personal data for the administration and enhancement of the contract with you. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined under C. II. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

##### **III. License Auditing:**

LogicalDOC Srl is using information about the frequency of your use of LogicalDOC and statistics of use of the different features in order to monitor if the agreed license restrictions are observed and in case we recognize that they are exceeded, we will contact you to suggest changing your license type. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. III is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR.

##### **IV. Feedback:**

If you place an inquiry with LogicalDOC by using the in product feedback feature or an online service, LogicalDOC Srl needs to process your personal data in order to answer your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. IV is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

##### **V. Paid license and servivces:**

When you use LogicalDOC and pay for a license or service, LogicalDOC Srl additionally collects information to support payment processing, which includes a payment token provided by our Payment Service Provider to identify the transaction. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. IV is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

##### **VI. Newsletter:**

If you sign up for LogicalDOC’s newsletter, LogicalDOC Srl processes your personal data in order to send you the newsletter. Legal basis to provide you with the newsletter is your consent according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR, which you may revoke at any time with effect for the future. In case you have a paid license, we may use your email address to send you information on similar products and services. Legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR, sec. 7 para. 3 Unfair Competition Act (" **UWG** ").

##### **VII. Support:**

In case you contact our support, we will process your personal data in order to answer your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. VII. Is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR.

##### **XII. Other:**

Where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to, we process your personal data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. e) GDPR.

#### **E. Recipients**

LogicalDOC Srl has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need to know interest in accessing personal data, will have access to your personal data. LogicalDOC employees, who administer and enhance the contractual relationship with you will receive access to your personal data. If you have a paid license, employees who are concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. In case you contact our support, our employees who are engaged in providing support will handle your personal data to the extent required to answer your request.

However, we also instruct third parties, such IT maintenance and storage service provider, to help us to operate our business. These third party providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide. LogicalDOC has chosen these third parties with due care and obligated them to confidentiality. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [privacy@logicaldoc.com](mailto:privacy@logicaldoc.com).

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

#### **F. Retention Periods for Personal Data**

LogicalDOC Srl retains your personal data for the duration of our contractual relationship with you, regardless if your subscription is for free or paid. Once this contractual relationship terminates, LogicalDOC Srl will delete your personal data, unless LogicalDOC Srl is legally obligated to retain personal data such as your name, your order form, and the date of the order, in accordance with Italian Commercial Code and/or Italian Tax Code for a minimum of ten years, if you payed for LogicalDOC.

#### **G. Statutory/contractual requirement**

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support.

#### **H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling**

LogicalDOC Srl does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making and profiling.

#### **I. Your Rights**

You may contact us either in writing or by email at privacy@logicaldoc.com in order to exercise the following rights to the extent you are entitled to so under applicable law:

  * You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
  * You may request a copy of your personal data;
  * You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data;
  * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights - have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.

Should you have any questions on the processing of your personal data by LogicalDOC Srl in relation to your contractual relationship, please contact [privacy@logicaldoc.com](mailto:privacy@logicaldoc.com).

### **2. Information concerning your responsible use of the Product**

When you use LogicalDOC, we are providing the product to you as a technical service that you may reasonably use. We technically assist you, as a processor, with connecting to other devices, initiating meetings, or the hosting of the contacts that you upload. You are responsible for utilizing LogicalDOC in accordance with the applicable laws, including data protection laws. The following section explains to you how LogicalDOC works.

#### **A. Personal Data processed through your use of LogicalDOC**

##### **I. Log files:**

In order to solve your issues we may ask you the log files of LogicalDOC, in this case the log files may contain personal data like emails or names.

##### **II. Meetings and Remote Control:**

When you participates in technical sessions, support sessions, presentations, video calls, and phone calls with LogicalDOC, LogicalDOC Srl will receive your **meeting ID** , email, **name, subject of the meeting, start and end date and time, time zone, and a password**. When you share your screen, please bear in mind that participants can see all items on your desktop. If you do not want to grant other participants access to your desktop, we recommend that you disable the screen share option under settings > close screen share.

During a LogicalDOC session, LogicalDOC Srl enables you to be seen by other participants through your build in device camera. Also LogicalDOC Srl enables you to record your presentations, video and phone calls.

#### **B. Data Usage**

LogicalDOC Srl is using all of the personal data described in section II. A. in order to provide you with the functionalities of LogicalDOC.

We will not share personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction. 

#### **C. Data Subjects Rights**

Data subjects may exercise certain rights in relation to the processing of their personal data through LogicalDOC towards you. As your technical service provider we may assist you to answer such request. Such rights might be accessing personal data, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, data portability and objection to the processing. Data subjects have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of their personal data.

Should you have any questions on the processing of personal data through LogicalDOC, please contact [privacy@logicaldoc.com](mailto:privacy@logicaldoc.com).
